Guide to the Stephen W. Jacobs papers, 1954-1978
Jacobs, Stephen W. papers, 1954-1978
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Stephen W. Jacobs papers, 1954-1978
15-2-1713
Stephen W. Jacobs, 1919-1978.
65.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, flyers, announcements, files, course notes and outlines, exams, photographs, clippings, and pamphlets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence and other materials related to Stephen W. Jacobs' career as Professor of Architecture at Cornell University and his involvement with historical preservation efforts.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Stephen W. Jacobs was a Professor of Architecture at Cornell University and a founder of Historic Ithaca, a historic preservation society in Ithaca, New York, serving as its president from 1968-1973. He was a director of the Society of Architectural Historians and a founder or member of several preservation organizations.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence with students and other professors; preservation society flyers, announcements and other material on their activities; files of the Society of Architectural Historians; material on architects; course notes, exams, papers, and outlines; material on historic preservation laws and possible funding by the National Trust for Historic Preservation; Wayne County (New York) study files with material on the social, political, cultural, and economic nature of a civilization as reflected in its architecture, including manuscript of the completed study and hundreds of photographs of buildings; and clippings, pamphlets, and Historic American Buildings Survey photographs covering preservation efforts in major American cities.
Also, slides of Wayne County, N.Y., photographed ca. 1965-1966 for Jacobs' book, Wayne County: The Aesthetic Heritage of a Rural Area: A Catalog for the Environment.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Jacobs, Stephen W.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; Society of Architectural Historians.; National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States.; Historic Ithaca, Inc.; Historic American Buildings Survey.
Subjects:
Architecture--History.; Architecture and society.; Architecture--Study and teaching.; Architecture--New York (State).; Historic buildings--Conservation and restoration.; College teachers.; Architectural historians.
Places:
Wayne County (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, A-Craig (Box 1)
- Correspondence, Crane-F (Box 2)
- Correspondence, G-I (Box 3)
- Correspondence, J-Maier (Box 4)
- Correspondence, Majewski-Q (Box 5)
- Correspondence, R-Slade (Box 6)
- Correspondence, Smith-Wodehouse (Box 7)
- Correspondence, Wolfe-Z; Organizations, A (note box 25 has beginning of this record set) (Box 8)
- Organizations, B-New York State Preservation League (Box 9)
- Organizations, Preservation League-SAH (Box 10)
- Organizations, SAH-Z and unfiled (Box 11)
- Architects, arranged by date of birth, before 1850 (Box 12)
- Architects, before 1850 and 1850-present (Box 13)
- Architects, 1850 to present (Box 14)
- Architects, 1850 to present, course notes (Box 15)
- Course notes (Box 16)
- Course notes (Box 17)
- Course notes (Box 18)
- Course notes (Box 19)
  includes summer institute notes
- Course notes (Box 20)
- Course notes (Box 21)
- Course notes (Box 22)
- Course notes and organizational files (goes with Box 8) (Box 23)
- Organizations and publishers (Box 24)
- Organizations (goes before Box 8) (Box 25)
- Wayne County study files, subjects (Box 26)
- Wayne County study files, subject and towns (Box 27)
- Wayne County study files, manuscript and photographs (one folder of oversized drawings removed and placed in map case--B. Huth, 1/21/87) (Box 28)
- Wayne County study files, photographs, also a 4" x 20" roll of Wayne County research material; U.S. Government (Box 29)
- U.S. Government material (Box 30)
- U.S. Government material, Geographical files, California (Box 31)
- Geographical files, California-Connecticut (Box 32)
- Geographical files, Washington, D.C.-Georgia (Box 33)
- Geographical files, Illinois-Maine (Box 34)
- Geographical files, Maryland-Massachusetts (Box 35)
- Geographical files, Massachusetts-New Hampshire (Box 36)
- Geographical files, New Jersey-Pennsylvania (except for New York State, which remain in Jacobs' office) (Box 37)
- Geographical files, Pennsylvania-Rhode Island (Box 38)
- Geographical files, South Carolina-Virginia (Box 39)
- Geographical files, Virginia-Wyoming, student papers (Box 40)
- Geography--International files, Canada-England (Box 41)
- Geography--International files, Scotland-France (Box 42)
- Geography--International files, France-Sweden (Box 43)
- Geography--International files, Finland-Columbia (Box 44)
- Geography--International files, Costa Rica-Japan and misc. (Box 45)
- Class notes (Box 46)
- Class notes and Wayne County study (Box 47)
- Wayne County study (Box 48)
- Wayne County study (Box 49)
- Wayne County study (Box 50)
- Original Jacobs acc. (September 1975) (Box 51)
- Miscellaneous University files; research files (September 12, 1979 acc.) (Box 52)
- Miscellaneous University files; research files (September 12, 1979 acc.) (Box 53)
- Miscellaneous University files; research files (September 12, 1979 acc.) (Box 54)
- Miscellaneous University files; research files (September 12, 1979 acc.) (Box 55)
- Miscellaneous files and notebooks (June 30, 1980 acc.) (Box 56)
- Miscellaneous files and notebooks (June 30, 1980 acc.) (Box 57)
- Course material, 1961-1978 (July 17, 1980 acc.) (Box 58)
- Course material, 1961-1978 (July 17, 1980 acc.) (Box 59)
- Course material, 1961-1978 (July 17, 1980 acc.) (Box 60)
- Slides of Wayne County scenes (Box 61)
- Slides of Wayne County scenes (Box 62)
- HAU, class materials, AAP files (Box 63)
- HAU, class materials, AAP files (Box 64)
- HAU, class materials, AAP files (Box 65)
- HAU, class materials, AAP files (Box 66)
- HAU, class materials, AAP files (Box 67)
- Primarily lectures, ca. 1954-1971 (Box 68)
- "Architectural Preservation: American Development and Antecedents Abroad," by S. W. J. and "City Design Through Conservation," by S. W. J. and Barclay Jones, volumes 1-2 (Box 69)
- Photographs and maps, Date unknown (Mapcase-folder 1)